Yesterday, they drafted your teammate,
Tre'von Moehrig. I was wondering how how
much are you looking forward to the
opportunity of playing with him at the
next level?
Yeah, no, I'm super excited. You know,
that's my boy. We're best friends and um
you know
being drafted is one thing, but you
know, being drafted to a team that
you know, I get to go somewhere with my
best friend and continue this, you know,
Bear Down brotherhood. I'm super excited
and
ready to take that leadership and you
know
turn Las Vegas up.
Dalton, this is Hondo Carpenter.
Congratulations on your journey to the
NFL. You have a unique ability. You are
a thumper in the run game, but you also
have the speed to cover slot receivers
and tight ends. Would you just talk
about that? It's a very unique skill set
for how you play. Can you discuss that
for us, please?
Yeah, I always say, you know, I was
brought up in football too late cuz
you know, I love to hit. You know,
there's no more I power, no more
fullbacks.
So, you know, you just got to develop as
the game goes and it's changing to you
know, more spread offenses. So, I really
had to develop my my pass coverage side
of the game and
you know, shout out to coach Gonzalez,
our DC at Arizona. He put me in great
opportunities to to allow me to expand
my defense to that standpoint and you
know, like I mentioned, you know, the
game is changing. So, you know, I got to
be ready for it and always had the
tackling ability and just the the
physical side. So, being able to
showcase my ball skills and all that,
you know,
just wanted to be a complete DB. Didn't
want to just be put in a box as you
know, a run fit safety or anything like
that.
Hi Dalton, just wondering what excites
you about coming to the Raiders and what
was the call like that you got today?
Yeah, no, I mean,
you know, the Raiders are are building
something special.
You know, young team up and coming and
we're going to do it the right way.
I'm excited to be a part of it and just
the phone call. Um you know, I seen it
pop up. You know, Las Vegas Nevada and
um you know, just seeing that pop up and
you know it instantly hit me that I'm
going to be there with Stukes
and it was it was one of a kind. Um
could barely hear the call cuz my mom
was crying so loud, but
just that moment is something I'm going
to remember forever.
Hey Dalton, Jesse Merrick with Silver
and Black Sports Network. You played for
four different defensive coordinators at
Arizona. That's obviously a lot. How
much did that kind of help you just wrap
your head around a bunch of different
schemes and also like how did it help
you grow your game in so many different
areas?
Yeah, I would say
it was huge cuz
you know, through the whole draft
process, just all the the Zooms and you
know, the scheme installs, um it made it
fairly easy cuz it was just defenses
that I've run and just like seen it, you
know, from you know, where there was
different lingo, but it it all was the
same in its own aspect and um
you know, it the growing part which is
you know, more opportunities to play
different positions, just boundary,
whether I was in the post or you know,
roll down safety or even going a little
bit of nickel. So,
you know, it's it was a crazy story and
just in the moment it seemed like
hectic, but
you know, I don't want my story to be
any other way and I'm just so thankful
for all the opportunities and the
coaches that have come through Arizona
and just taught me and grew my my
football knowledge.
Dalton, what does it say about the
current staff at UA? There's been so
many there, but the fact that they're
putting two of you guys in the NFL and
there's a lot of talent brewing there.
What's it just say about the future of
of UA football?
Yeah, um
you know, they say Arizona's a a
basketball school. Um
you know, but we're bringing football to
Tucson. You know, we're a football and
basketball school and
you know, shout out to the coaches.
You know, coach coach B, coach Brennan
came in. You know, new team, new staff
had to throw together something real
quick and
you know, that 24 season didn't go our
way and
I'm just glad me and the guys got to
stick together and trust him.
I love the way he coaches and I love the
way that he just lets his players be his
players and treats us like you know, his
sons, all 110 of us and
you know, lets his coaches, you know,
his OC, you know, coach Daggy and his
DC, coach Gonzalez, he lets them do
their job and he has full trust in them
and you know, seeing that trust in his
coaches and he also trusts his players
the same way. It just allows us to trust
him and just really be a family that
just wants to succeed together.
Hey, what's up, man? I have two for you.
One real quick. You talked about
[clears throat] your relationship with
Tre'von. Has he has he reached out? I
guess what was that conversation like
real quick? Yeah,
I called him real quick and
he just couldn't believe it and he did
mention he was like, I think this is the
best day of my life. Um just like I
mentioned earlier, it's one thing to be
drafted and I'm so grateful to be a
Raider and then
on top of that, I get to I get to do it
with Stukes, you know, so this is
probably
the best day of our lives for both of
us. And the other one is you you
obviously you've been pretty physical,
good against the run throughout your
career. Look like you took a pretty big
step forward in your coverage last year.
I was wondering if that was just
personal improvement or is that scheme?
I guess what what was the
the development there? Yeah, I would say
it's a a bit of both. Um
you know, I mentioned earlier, you know,
the game is moving fast and it's going
to spread offenses and you know
it's all about the ball. So, I was
really working on that in the off season
and made that a big emphasis, you know,
in my mindset you know, going into
practices and games like I got to get
the ball. I got to you know, get picked,
PBUs, whatever it is
and then you know, I would say that also
comes with scheme.
Coach Gonzalez put me in great
opportunities, you know, to make plays
and you know, be in the right position
to to get actions and get my hand on the
ball. So,
I say it makes a both and I'm so
thankful that you know
putting in the work and you know, was
able to you know, get around the ball
more and plus you know, coach G
make me and believing in me and trust me
to be in those opportunities to do it.
Last one, Sam. Go ahead.
Hey there,
you just brought up your versatility a
couple questions ago. Tre'von moved
around a ton at Arizona as well. I'm
just wondering where you feel that your
best fit in the NFL is going to be and
also kind of just how that versatility
adds another aspect to your game.
Yeah, I would just say
you know, whatever my role is, you know,
special teams, um backup, starter, you
know, I'm going to bring 100% and um I
feel like I can play anywhere. I'm not
going to say anywhere as far as you
know, outside at corner, but
you know, I'm ready to you know,
whatever my role is, you know, I'm I'm
there to do it. Whether that's nickel,
that you know, boundary safety spot,
free safety spot. I'm just ready to be a
Raider and get rolling.
Awesome. Thanks, Dalton. Appreciate you.
Of course. Thank you all.